question of the seven years of
tribulation put a five in the chat if
you have heard about this seven year
tribulation
um
teaching before
now uh I kind of wanted to
give a little introduction to my slides
in fact let me come back to the screen
yeah
um so I have a I have an amazing slide
team if you guys have been blessed by
the slides you have been seeing over the
last uh several weeks uh that is my
slide team and they have done uh an
amazing job they've done an amazing job
uh put a seven in the chat me and all
these numbers put a seven in the chat if
you have been uh
um blessed by these slides now
uh the reason I'm talking about this
today is because
um I will usually send my my notes
uh to the slide team and then they'll
put together the slide and they'll look
at my notes and I just send them the the
uh the verses so they don't know where
I'm going with my sermon at all uh and
they'll usually try to kind of fit the
theme with with uh you know what what
they believe uh my sermon is going to be
about well
um these slides today basic my slide
team sent a message to me and it is a
message that my wife has uh you've heard
my wife uh give this message before
particularly when I'm doing prophecy
uh she says and you can put the slide
back up you can actually put the slide
at me on the screen if you can she says
listen when you present on Prophecy I
want you to present it in such a way
that even a child could understand it
even a child could understand it and so
as I was looking through the slides that
were created I said okay yeah they want
me to really really really really break
this down because this particular
prophecy
uh can be for a lot of people uh a
difficult profit prophecy something hard
to understand so it is my promise to you
by the grace of God today that we're
gonna break this down so that a child
can understand right we're going to be
in a classroom setting today
and we're going to break this down so
that every one of you those of you that
are watching now and those of you that
will watch in the future will understand
this very easily okay so with that
let's have a word of prayer and we're
gonna get into the message uh for today
we're gonna get into the message The
Seven Year tribulation let's pray
Heavenly Father we asked Laura that uh
as the word of God is open you would
bless us Lord that you would speak
through me Lord that um
you would help me to make this uh as
simple so simple that a child can
understand
we pray this in the precious and holy
name of Jesus may your name be lifted up
in Jesus name we pray amen amen all
right let's go let's go so what is this
seven year
tribulation
uh teaching about
basically it is the idea that at the end
of time there's going to be this seven
year period in which various things
happen some of those things are that
Satan himself is going to make a treaty
and this is what begins the seven this
seven year period Satan himself is going
to make a treaty
um or a uh an agreement uh with the
nation of Israel
this agreement will last seven years and
in the middle of the seven years uh the
Antichrist will break this Covenant this
treaty and this will kick off the time
of trouble such as never was so that's
the theory that's the teaching by the
way this is often connected with the
Rapture
um so you know a lot of people ask the
question the teaching of the Rapture I
should say a lot of people ask a
question well do you think that the
church will be raptured before the seven
years in the middle of the seven years
or after the seven years now
multitudes
multitudes of Christians believe
this seven year tribulation teaching
and uh with that you would you would uh
think that there is a lot in the Bible
that talks about this seven year uh
Theory this seven year treaty but in
actuality there is only one verse that
is used to teach this seven year
tribulation one verse that verse is
found in the Book of Daniel chapter nine
Daniel chapter nine let's go to the
screen Daniel chapter 9
Daniel chapter 9 and verse 27 this is
the verse
the Bible says here and he shall confirm
the Covenant with many for one week and
in the midst of the week
he shall cause the sacrifice and the
oblation to cease
and for the overspreading of
Abominations he shall make it desolate
even until the consummation and that
determines shall be poured out upon the
desolate now
I know this verse in and of itself seems
pretty complex
but again what what many Christians
teach when reading this verse is that uh
this confirming of the Covenant is done
by the Antichrist the one week which
would be seven days
is symbolic of one of seven years so a
day would equal a year and that's where
they get the seven years from right one
prophetic week seven prophetic days
would equal in reality seven years not
seven days and so in the midst of this
seven year period so three and a half
years in uh uh he would uh cause the
Covenant or he would uh uh stop the
sacrifices that are occurring in a
Temple and so what this means is that
many Christians believe there's going to
be a rebuilt temple in the future this
rebuilt Temple once a temple is rebuilt
they say this is a sign of the end times
when the temple is rebuilt
sacrifices and offerings will be started
up again and it will be based upon this
treaty with Israel and so that's why you
hear a lot of people in prophetic
circles talking about waiting for a
temple to be rebuilt in Jerusalem and
when that happens you know all these
things are going to kind of kick off
Antichrist is going to make a treaty but
it three and a half years into this
seven year period he's gonna stop the
sacrifices and offerings and this is
what begins the time of trouble three
and a half years of persecution okay
so the question is
did is this text actually saying all
that is this text saying any of that
well to understand
let's go back
to the Book of Daniel the very same
chapter Daniel chapter 9 and we're gonna
break this down verse by verse you see
the seven year this seven year period
is actually part of a larger prophecy
called the 70 week prophecy
so and it's found in Daniel 9.
the entire prophecy is 70 weeks but what
many Christians believe is that the the
69 weeks
have already come to pass
came to pass a long time ago
but the 70th week which would be the
last seven years put a one in the chat
if you understand
what I just shared okay the last
seven years of this 70-week prophecy so
if I can do it this way
if one week
prophetically equals seven years there
are 70 weeks
so it would be 70 weeks 70 times
seven seven days in a week 70 times
seven would equal four hundred and
ninety
so
of this 490
prophetic days these 490 days would
equal
490 years
so most Christians believe that
483 of those years or 69 of those weeks
69 times 7 is
483. so those 483 years or 69 prophetic
weeks have already happened they
happened in the past a long time ago but
the the 70th week or the last seven
years is yet future
okay
so what we want to do is we want to go
to the Book of Daniel and we want to
start from verse 1 just to catch the
context of this 70-week prophecy so
let's go ahead let's begin reading
Daniel 9 verse 1 in the first year of
Darius son of of Lazarus of the Seas of
the medes which was made King over the
realm of the Chaldeans in the first year
of his Reign I Daniel understood my
books the number of the years where of
the word of the Lord came to Jeremiah
the prophet that he would accomplish 70
years in the desolations of Jerusalem
okay so let's just pause for a second
and um let's give some context
Daniel the Prophet that is writing
is living in Babylon
now why is he in Babylon he's in Babylon
because the children of Israel were
taken captive into Babylon
they were taken captive because of
Disobedience because of because of
rebellion and God told them that they
were gonna they were going to spend 70
years in Babylon
okay
70 years in Babylon so I'm seeing there
that there is no sermon link up on
all right I'ma leave my team to to look
at that but check out that that uh uh
Sam he's saying there's no live sermon
on YouTube so please just look into that
okay
so Babylon
the Jews children of Israel are in
Babylonian captivity and they have been
there for 70 years just as God said now
this 70 years is not the 70 weeks that's
a totally different prophecy
70 years they have been in Babylonian
captivity and at the end of this period
this is when Daniel is writing in fact
we just read that the middle Persian
Empire is now reigning the middle
Persian Empire had overthrown Babylon
and this is the Empire that's about to
let the Jews return out of captivity go
back and build their Temple if you will
which had been destroyed during the
Babylonian Siege okay so that's the
context of Daniel chapter 9. Babylon has
just Fallen
Daniel is is is uh looking at this
70-year prophecy and then he begins this
prayer so notice with me verse two
Daniel 9 verse 3 rather
and I set my face unto the Lord God to
seek by prayer and supplications with
fasting and sackcloth and Ashes and I
prayed unto the Lord my God and made my
confession and said oh Lord the great
and Dreadful God keeping the Covenant of
and mercy to them that love him and to
them that keep his Commandments
reading on
we have sinned and have committed
iniquity and have done wickedly and have
rebelled even by departing from thy
precepts and from that judgment
neither have we hearken unto thy
servants the prophets which spake in thy
name to our Kings our princes and our
fathers and to all the people of the
Land O Lord righteousness belongeth unto
thee but unto us confusion of faces as
at this day to the men of Judah and to
the inhabitants of Jerusalem and unto
all Israel that are near and that are
far off through all the countries
whether thou has driven them because of
their trespasses that they have
trespassed against thee
verse 8. the Lord this Lord
this O Lord to us belong with confusion
of Faith to our Kings to our princes and
to our fathers because we have sinned
against thee to the Lord Our God belong
with mercies and forgiveness though we
have rebelled against him
neither have we obeyed the voice of the
Lord Our God to walk in his laws
which he set before us by his servants
the prophets verse 11 yea all Israel
have transgressed thy law even by The
Parting that they might not obey thy
voice
therefore the curse is poured out upon
us and the oath that is written in the
law of Moses the servant of God because
we have sinned against him
as it is written in the law of Moses all
this evil has come upon us yet made me
not our prayer before the Lord Our God
that we might turn from our iniquities
and understand thy truth
therefore hath the Lord watched upon
this watched upon the evil and brought
it upon us for the Lord our God is
righteous in all his Works which he
doeth for we obeyed not his voice and
now O Lord Our God thou has brought thy
people forth out of the land of Egypt
with a mighty hand and has gotten the
renowned as at this day we have sinned
we have done wickedly
now therefore o God hear the prayer of
thy servant and his supplication and
cause thy face to shine upon thy
Sanctuary that is desolate for the
Lord's Sake O my God inclined by near
and hear open thine eyes and behold our
desolations and the city which is called
by thy name for we do not present our
supplications before the our
righteousness but for thy great Mercy
oh Lord
forgive
forgive put that word in the chat for me
please oh Lord
forgive O Lord hearken and do
do not defer for thine own sake oh my
God for thy City and thy people are
called by thy name now
what I need you to understand is this
let's let's let's I'm gonna come back to
that in a moment
Daniel is praying a prayer of confession
and he's asking for forgiveness that's
what he's doing why because the children
of Israel
sinned against God that's why they ended
up in Babylonian captivity
all right are you following so far
So Daniel is praying this prayer of
confession and he's going through the
history of Israel in this prayer
now why is that significant because you
see in Exodus 19 and verse 5 the Bible
tells us
now therefore if you'll obey my voice
indeed and keep my Covenant
then you shall be a peculiar treasure
unto me above all the people for all the
Earth is mine now I want you to notice
that if what does if mean in the what is
if the word if what does it signify
it signifies
a condition
if you do this then X Y and Z will
happen so let me ask you a question when
God speaks in Exodus 19 5 and says now
therefore if you will obey my voice
indeed and keep my Covenant then you
shall be a peculiar treasure onto me
above all the people for all the Earth
is mine what does that verse mean
let me ask you a question does this
verse mean that no matter what Israel
does they will be a peculiar treasure
unto God no matter what yes or no
yes or no
it doesn't matter what the nation of
Israel does they will be a peculiar
treasure to God no matter what is that
what the text is saying
absolutely not
the text actually says if if you obey if
you obey my voice then so there was a
condition right the condition of being
God's peculiar people God's peculiar
treasure was obedience if you obey my
voice
verse 9 verse 6 goes on to say
and you shall be unto me a kingdom of
priests and a holy nation these are the
words that thou shall speak unto the
children of Israel and so
God is saying here I want you to
understand
that if you're to be a kingdom of priest
to me a holy nation
it will be because you obeyed my voice
it was conditional put that word in the
chat again for me please
conditional it was conditional now I
want you to notice the results of the
condition okay so there's a if then
so there's got to be a if you obey then
this if you don't obey then that so
let's see what this is The Book of
Leviticus chapter 26 verse 3 says this
if you walk in my statutes and keep my
Commandments and do them
then will I give you rain in due season
and the land shall yield her increase
and the Trees of the field shall yield
her fruit all right so we see here that
God is just laying out promises if your
baby
these are the promises you're going to
receive and he lists a bunch of them but
then it goes on to say
in Leviticus 26 Leviticus 26 and verse
. let me go back
okay
and if you want contrary unto me and
will not hearken unto me I will bring
seven times more plagues upon you
according to your sins and I will also
send wild beasts like lions and bears
and leopards and and and and and beasts
with four without ten horns things of
that nature I will send wild beasts
among you which shall rob you of your
children and destroy your cattle and
make you fewer number and your highways
shall be desolate and I will make your
cities waste and bring your sanctuaries
onto desolation and I will not smell the
savior of your sweet orders and I will
bring the land into desolation and your
enemies which dwell therein shall be
astonished at it I will scatter you
among the Heathen and will draw out a
sword after you and your land shall be
desolate and your city's waste
now let's pause for a second
let's pause for a second
so what we see here is very clear
it's very clear
God says you obey me these are the
blessings you disobey these are the
curses why are the children of Israel in
Babylon why are they in Babylon for 70
years
because they chose what the blessings or
the curses put it in the chat for me
please what do they choose the blessings
of the curses
they chose to reject the voice of God
and as a result curses Came Upon them
that's why they're in Babylonian
captivity by the way the Book of Daniel
describes the kingdom of Babylon as a
lion and then middle Persia as a bear
and then Greece as a leopard and then
Rome as this fourth nondescript Beast
with ten horns so when God was saying
back there in Leviticus I will send wild
beasts among you
that will rob you of your children and
leave your land desolate he was talking
about these nations not literal beasts
okay
so
notice what God goes on to say here
notice what God goes on to say in
Leviticus 26 verse we're going to go
back to verse let's see
Leviticus 26 and verse
verse 41.
verse 40. and they that are left of you
shall Pine away in their iniquity in
your enemy's land where are the children
of Israel they're in Babylon
and also in the iniquity of their father
upon away with them now notice the very
next verse
if they saw confess their iniquity and
the iniquity of their fathers and their
trespasses which they have trespassed
against me and that also they have
walked contrary unto me
and that they I'm sorry
um next slide
and that I have also walked contrary
unto them and have brought them into the
land of their enemies
if then their uncircumcised Hearts be
humbled and then they accept of the
punishment of their iniquity then will I
remember the Covenant with Jacob and
also my Covenant with Isaac and also my
Covenant with Abraham will I remember
and I will remember the land let me ask
you a question guys
what is Daniel doing in Daniel chapter
9.
what is he doing on behalf of his people
what is he doing
on behalf of Israel
come on y'all help me out what is Daniel
doing on behalf of Israel
let's go back to the screen Daniel 9
verse 20.
so we've just seen all of Daniel's words
and notice what Daniel says and while I
was speaking and praying and confessing
my sin and the sin of my people is real
and presenting my supplication before
the Lord my God for the Holy Mountain of
my God
all right let's come back I want to
pause it we're taking this slow listen
what is God doing here
what is Daniel doing here
he's actually fulfilling the very thing
we just read in Leviticus 26 he is
praying on behalf of a rebellious people
he's interceding on behalf of a
rebellious people he's praying for Mercy
he's praying for forgiveness and and God
says if you do this remember he said I
will remember the Covenant the Covenant
that I made with Abraham and Isaac and
Jacob well what is that Covenant what is
that Covenant
what was the major promise to Abraham
Isaac and Jacob let's go back to the
screen
Galatians chapter 3 verse 16 tells us
this and now to Abraham and his seed
were the promises made
he saith not and to seeds as of many but
as of one
and to thy seed which is who everyone
Christ
come back with me
let's come back come back to the screen
God says if you repent I'm going to
remember the promise I gave you what is
the promise I gave you
I will put enmity between thee and the
woman between thy seed and her seat in
other words I'm gonna send the seed I'm
gonna send someone
that is going to be the Fulfillment of
the promise
so when Daniel is praying because Israel
has rebelled and they have fallen short
of what God called them to do what God
called them to be Daniel is not
interested in on behalf of his people
and beloved
in doing that
in representing for his people the
spirit of confession and humility
God is about to speak to Daniel
concerning the promised Messiah put a
one in the chat if y'all are following
so far
put a one in the chat if you're
following so far
we're gonna see let's go back to Daniel
chapter nine
and let's read from verse 20.
it says and while I was speaking and
praying and confessing my sin and the
sin of My People Israel and presenting
my supplication before the Lord my God
for the Holy Mountain of my God yea
while I was speaking in prayer even the
man Gabriel whom I had seen in the
vision at the beginning being caused to
fly swiftly touch me at about the time
of the evening oblation
reading on
and he informed me and talked with me
and said oh Daniel I am now come forth
to give these skill and understanding at
the beginning of my supplication the
Commandment came forth and I am come to
show thee for thou art greatly beloved
understand the matter therefore and
consider the vision and now
we are introduced
to Daniel 9
verse 24.
70 weeks are determined upon thy people
and upon thy Holy City to finish the
transgression and to make an end of sins
and to make reconciliation for iniquity
and to bring an everlasting
righteousness and to seal up the vision
and prophecy and to anoint the most holy
okay let's let's come back to the screen
and what I want you to catch beloved is
this
it is an answer to Daniel's prayer that
this 70-week prophecy is given what is
Daniel doing he's pleading for
forgiveness put that word in the chat
again for me please he's pleading for
what forgiveness
and then the angel comes to him and says
Daniel 70 weeks
now y'all help me
70 weeks how many days in a week
seven
days
so 70 weeks would be 70
times
seven
what do we know about that number 70
times 7.
we know that at one point Peter is
speaking to Jesus and he says how often
shall someone sin against me and I
forgive them till seven times I mean
that that's a lot that's being really
merciful if I let you do something seven
times and forgive you each time and God
said Jesus says I say not unto you until
seven times but until Seventy Times
Seven this is the number of forgiveness
of God you see man's forgiveness is
seven times
all right man I forgive you but then we
run short of patience
Divine forgiveness is 70 times seven so
let's put this together then the people
of Israel have rebelled against God they
have sinned against God and they are in
captivity in Babylonian captivity Daniel
the Prophet prays on behalf of the
people and an answer to this prayer the
angel comes and says God is extending to
you
are y'all with me God is extending to
you a period of Grace a period of Mercy
he's going to to extend Mercy to you in
a very specific way he's going to extend
forgiveness to you in a very specific
way
something's going to happen towards the
end of this 70 times 7 that is going to
give you an opportunity
to be forgiven
let's go back to the screen
let's go back to the screen because I
need you to note these things 70 weeks
are determined upon your people and upon
your whole in other words y'all have 70
weeks I'm giving you 70 weeks 70 times
seven
490 years to do something
finish a transgression make an end of
sins make reconciliation for iniquity
bring an everlasting righteousness seal
of division and prophecy and to anoint
the most holy now
transgression
to finish the transgression what
transgression what transgression
the book of Isaiah 58 verse 1 tells us
this cry aloud spare not lift up thy
voice like a trumpet and show my people
their what transgression and the house
of Jacob their sins the transgressions
that were to be brought to an end you
are transgressing against me as your God
and I am giving you a certain time to
stop transgressing against me now how
would this transgression come to an end
do you think that Israel had the power
in and of themselves to bring an end to
transgression the answer is no there is
only one individual that can bring an
end to transgressions notice with me
Isaiah 59 and verse 20 the Bible says
and the Redeemer shall come to Zion and
then that turn from transgression and on
to them that turn from transgression in
Jacob saith the Lord I need you to
understand that the very purpose of
Jesus coming to the world was to put an
end to the transgressions of his people
and how would he do that
by what mechanism would Jesus put an end
to transgression we can read about it in
the very next verse because remember Not
only was he was he gonna was there to be
at the end of sin
and what's interesting about this is
that in Leviticus chapter 7 verse 7 that
word for sin
is translated as Sin
offering
sin offering
Leviticus 7 7 as the sin offering is
that's the same word used in Daniel
chapter nine so is a trespass offering
for there is one law for them in other
words
there would be an end of offering for
sin
and beloved guess how offering for sins
ended according to the book of Hebrews
chapter 10 verse 17 and their sins and
their iniquities will I remember no more
now where there is remission of these
there is no more offering for sin can
y'all come back to the screen for a
second I don't need y'all to catch this
so far an end of transgression could
only be done through the Messiah an end
of sin and sin offerings could only be
done through the offering up of the
Messiah are y'all following me so far
in other words
the very one who has power to Grant
forgiveness is coming to you at the end
of this Seventy Times Seven if you
receive him and accept him you are
forgiven
put a one in the chat if y'all catch
this
put a one in the chat if you're
following the the same seven-week
prophecy went on to say not only an end
of transgressions an end of sin but to
make reconciliation for iniquity beloved
there is only one individual that could
make reconciliation for iniquity and
that is Jesus Hebrews chapter 2 and
verse 17. Hebrews chapter 2 and verse 17
the Bible says
wherefore in all things it behooved him
it behooved him to be made like unto his
Brethren that he might be a merciful and
faithful high priest in things
pertaining to God to make reconciliation
for the sins of the people
so far three for three y'all he was
going to there was going to be an end of
transgressions
there was going to be an end of sin and
there would be reconciliation for
iniquity all of these things are
pointing to the coming of Jesus Christ
it also goes on to say that he would
bring that there would bring in
Everlasting righteousness
Everlasting righteousness I need you to
understand according to the book of
Psalm 119 and 142 thy righteousness is
an everlasting righteousness and thy law
is truth Jesus himself was that
Everlasting righteousness when he came
he would be ushering in a type of
righteousness that was not available to
man before
the Everlasting righteousness of Christ
the prophecy goes on to say I need I'm
just breaking down this 70 week for you
so you can see it in the 70 weeks was in
essence pointing to the coming of the
Messiah
the prophecy also said that he would see
that that during his 70 weeks uh there
would be a sealing up of the vision and
prophecy so what does it mean a sealing
up of the vision and prophecy the Bible
says in second Timothy chapter 2 verse
19 nevertheless the foundation of God's
stand is sure
having this seal the Lord knows them
that are his
and again
we read in Matthew chapter 27 verse 26
or verse 65
that when pilate was trying to make sure
of the Tomb make sure that Jesus did not
come out the tomb pilate said unto them
you have a watch go your way and make it
as sure as you can so they went and made
the Sepulcher Shore sealing the stone
and setting a watch
when something is sealed
it makes it a sure thing
a certain thing
if I can rephrase it this way
Jesus is the one who seals the
prophecies
the visions and the Prophecies of all
the prophets that came before Jesus is
the Seal of the Visions he is the Seal
of the prophets and the Bible is telling
us that in this 70-week prophecy it
would be so precise it would be as Jesus
making it a sure thing it cannot be
moved it cannot be altered it is
definitive it proves beyond a shadow of
a doubt that Jesus is who he says he is
because he comes right on time
the same seven-week prophecy goes on to
say that he would anoint the most holy
now that word Most Holy in the Hebrew is
kodesh and it is used to apply to two
things one the sanctuary and two people
notice with me
Psalm 77 verse 13 the Bible says here
thy way o God is in the sanctuary the
word used there is kodesh so some way in
some way the 70 week prophecy would
point to the anointing of a sanctuary at
the end of this time period
you know the Bible tells us in Hebrews
chapter 8 verse 1.
in Hebrews chapter 8 and verse 1 Hebrews
chapter 8 verse 1 must slides are kind
of going a little bit crazy here my uh
pointer is just a little bit behind
um
Hebrews chapter 8 verse one I'm just
going to read this the Bible says now of
the things which we have spoken this is
the sum we have such a high priest who
is set on the right hand of the Throne
of the majesties in the heavens a
minister of the sanctuary and of the
true Tabernacle which the Lord pitched
and not man now Daniel 12 7 is up on the
screen but I'm reading Hebrews chapter 8
verse 1 and 2. and Hebrews chapter 8
verse 1 and 2 is telling us that Jesus
upon his death burial in Resurrection
ascended to begin working in a Heavenly
Sanctuary that is the temple the
sanctuary the kodesh that was anointed
in this 70-week prophecy
but not only does Kadesh point to to the
sanctuary it points to the people Daniel
7 verse 12 the Bible says here
and I heard the man clothed in linen
which was upon the waters of the rivers
when he when he had held up his right
hand and his left went to heaven and
swear by him that liveth forever that
this will be four times and a half and
when he shot up accomplished
to scatter the power of the Holy people
the word there is kodesh
kodesh kodesh
so then come back with me
what was said to happen here is that
sometime towards the end of the seventh
week prophecy there would be anointing
of the temple and there would be an
anointing of the people y'all remember
what happened on the day of Pentecost
yes you remember that
on the day of Pentecost in Acts chapter
2 Acts chapter 2 and verse 1 when the
day of Pentecost was fully come they
were all with one Accord
in one place
verse 2.
and suddenly there appeared a sound from
Heaven as of a rushing Mighty Wind
and they are appeared unto them cloven
tongues like as a fire and it sat on
each of them
do y'all understand what's going on here
every part of this prophecy is referring
is referring to something that would
occur through the coming of the Messiah
the the the finishing of transgression
and of sin reconciliation for iniquity
right the anointing of the most holy
right the the the the the the sealing of
the vision and the prophecy all of these
things that were to occur were pointing
to the coming of the Messiah
all right
so so far so good now we got to get into
the timing of this so we know what to
expect now we get to verse 25 and this
is what verse 25 says this no no this
therefore and understand that from the
going forth of the Commandment to
restore and to build Jerusalem unto the
Messiah the prince shall be seven weeks
and three score which would be 60 and
two weeks the street shall be built
again and the wall even in trouble this
time okay so let's break this down
let's break this down
so
the angel says to Daniel
if you begin Counting
from the decree
which will be given to restore Jerusalem
if you count 69 weeks that would be
seven weeks and three score and two so
three scores 60 and 2 would be 62. 62
weeks plus seven weeks equals 69 weeks
did y'all catch that we're doing a
little bit of math here
the angel says if you begin from a
certain point the decree in which you
all will be allowed to rebuild your city
if you start from that decree and count
69 weeks it's going to bring you to the
Messiah
which means the anointed one which means
if we start from the decree and count 69
weeks or
483 years out of the full 490 years that
is going to bring you to the anointing
of Jesus
which identifies him as the Messiah
okay so how do we do this math
how do we start counting
well notice with me notice with me
okay here we go let's go to the screen
there were a total of four decrees given
a total of four decrees given different
decrees that revolved around the
rebuilding of the city or the sanctuary
the first decree was given by Cyrus
536 BC
that decree had to do with the Jews
going back to rebuild the sanctuary not
the city but the sanctuary but that's
not what the prophecy says the prophecy
says no therefore and understand that
from the going forth of the command to
restore and to build Jerusalem
so Cyrus's decree 536
Darius followed another decree Darius
gave another decree this was in 520 A.D
you find this in Ezra chapter four you
find Cyrus is the Korean Ezra chapter
one both of these decrees had to do with
the building of the sanctuary
there was a third decree given in 457 BC
by artaxerxes and he gave another one in
445 now the decree in 457 BC found in
Ezra chapter 7 was a decree that
actually dealt with setting up
magistrates and judges this is the
decree that we should begin counting
from let me show you in Isaiah chapter 1
verse 26 the Bible literally says and I
will restore thy judges as at the first
and by counselors as at the beginning
afterward shalta be called the city of
righteousness the faithful City
so what does Isaiah say will be the sign
that they are again the city of
righteousness the faithful City when the
judges or the magistrates are restored
meaning you are running your own City
again
well please note with me that in the
book of Ezra
Ezra chapter 7
Ezra chapter seven this is what I'm
gonna do
bring my slides up here because my uh
uh
this pointer is not working too well
here Ezra chapter 7 verse 25 know what
the Bible says
and thou Ezra after this is the this is
the decree given by artist Xerxes in 457
BC it's recorded in Ezra chapter seven
in this decree it literally reads and
thou Ezra after the wisdom of God that
is in thine hand set magistrates and
judges which may judge all the people
that are beyond the river all such as
know the laws of thy God and teach them
that know them not so now we have the
actual decree where judges are you are
you cannot have your own judicial system
that decree was given in 457 BC and
here's what happens listen
if you go
if you go from 457 BC and you add
69 weeks or
483 years you come to the year
27 A.D
put a one in the chat if you are
following this
27 A.D the question is what happened in
27 A.D
27 A.D is a very specific year the Bible
says in Luke chapter 3 verses 1-3 now in
the 15th year
of the reign of Tiberius Caesar Pontius
Pilate being governor of Judea and Herod
being Ted truck of Galilee Annis and
Cafe
is the being the high priest the word of
God came unto John the son of Zacharias
in the wilderness and he came into all
the country about Jordan preaching the
baptism of repentance for the remission
of sins the 15th year of the reign of
Tiberius is no is 27 A.D it is the very
year that Jesus is Anointed is baptized
by John the Baptist Jesus answering said
unto him suffered to be so for now for
thus it becometh us to fulfill all
righteousness and then John the Baptist
baptizes Jesus the Bible says in Matthew
3 16 and when he was baptized Jesus went
up straightway out of the water and lo
the heavens were open unto him and he
saw the spirit of God descending like a
dove and lighting upon him and law of
voice from him haven't seen this is my
beloved Son in whom I am well pleased
Jesus is Anointed meaning the word
Messiah means anointed he's identified
for the first time in his public
ministry as the Messiah
exactly as the prophecy stated now
after Jesus is Anointed The Bible says
from that time Jesus began to preach and
to say repent for the Kingdom of Heaven
is at hand now what is this message what
is the message that Jesus is coming with
Malachi chapter 3 verse 1 tells us
because there it says behold
I will send my messenger and he shall
prepare the way before me and the Lord
whom you seek shall suddenly come to his
Temple even the messenger of the
Covenant whom you delight and behold
he shall come saith the Lord now I got a
question for you who is the messenger of
the Covenant
who is the messenger of the Covenant
it is none other than Jesus himself
Jesus is the messenger of the Covenant
when we're reading Daniel chapter 9
beloved the Covenant
is made
not by Satan
Satan doesn't make a covenant y'all it's
Jesus
and we're given the very timing of the
arrival of this messenger of the
Covenant
let's keep moving I want y'all to catch
this
so so so the prophecy now we get to
verse 26 and it says and after three
score in two weeks in other words after
the 69 weeks after he has been anointed
Messiah be cut off
but not for himself
now y'all understand this right
you understand
that Jesus was cut off
but it wasn't cut off for himself
he was cut off for others he was cut off
for his people why because he took their
sins upon himself
are y'all with me
now now follow this carefully because
here here is where the Christian world
gets thrown off
verse 26
. it says and the people of the prince
that shall come
shall destroy the city and the sanctuary
and the end thereof shall be with a
flood unto the end of the war
desolations are determined
now here's what I want you to understand
the people of the prince that shall come
shall destroy the city and the sanctuary
this
is talking about what happens
with the death of Jesus
who is this Prince
that shall come
that shall come notice with me John
chapter 14. John chapter 14
verse 30. Jesus said this he said
hereafter
I will not talk much with you for the
prince of this world cometh and has
nothing in me
who is the prince that would be coming
just around the time that the Messiah is
being cut off Jesus tells us it's the
prince of this world it's Satan himself
he is the prince of this world he is the
one that when he comes
he would lead his people remember the
Romans
destroyed the city and the temple
why did they destroy the city in the
temple because the very offer of
forgiveness that God had extended to his
people they chose to do what
they said no thank you
no thank you
and as a result of this Jesus dies on
behalf of his people they reject his
sacrifice you're not the Messiah we
reject you and as a result the pr the
people of the prince that was to come
that is Satan who was cast down at the
cross Satan who was rejected Satan who
who Jesus said I saw him fall like
lightning from Heaven Satan who says
look the prince of this world is coming
and he has nothing in me
that Prince Satan himself led the Roman
army to destroy the city and the temple
in 70 A.D
are y'all following put a one in the
chat if you're following
so the Bible now says this watch this
this is where Christians really get
thrown off because the very next verse
says this Daniel 9 27.
and he shall confirm the Covenant with
many for one week
you see beloved this is where the Gap
theory is introduced
the Christian World by and large
believes that the He Who Shall confirm
the Covenant with many for one week
that's the verse we open with that this
he is Satan
they think that it's the prince remember
when Jesus said the prince that cometh
they think that it's this Prince that's
going to confirm the Covenant with one
week no so so what they do is this they
say well look the 69 weeks was fulfilled
in Jesus yes Jesus came he was anointed
and we get that but then the stuff in
verse 27 hasn't happened yet this
Covenant with with many for one week it
hasn't happened yet so that 70th week
must be sometime in the distant future
so they impose what they call a gap
Theory
which basically says there is a gap
between the 69th week and the 70th week
so the 70th week is the is the is the
time when Satan makes this Covenant with
Israel for seven years and in the middle
of the seven years the Covenant is
broken and then you got this time of
trouble so here's my question for you
let's come back for a moment
okay
so if God said I'm giving you 15 minutes
to do something
and then you get to that 14th minute
and then you're like well you know what
let's put a pause in this 14 minutes
I'm gonna go ahead and like you know
grab some food you know maybe visit some
family and friends I know I got a couple
of classes to study for and
um
you know man I think I want to like
go into a new career so let me check
that out and then uh let me do X Y and Z
but it's not technically 15 minutes yet
because I've paused at 14 minutes so I'm
gonna do my stuff and then when I come
back I'll unpause and let the last the
15th minute play out
um
would that be 15 minutes
that would be longer than 15 minutes
right let me ask something is God wise
enough
that if a prophecy was to last from 457
BC until the very end of time is God
wise enough where he could have given a
prophecy that lasted that long and said
okay instead of 70 weeks it's going to
be 5 000 weeks I don't know just just
isn't it it's got is God can God do that
it's Gonna Last a thousand weeks
yeah time doesn't work like that
if God meant for a prophecy to last
x amount of time he's going to give us
that time
to impose a gap in this 70-week prophecy
is up it makes absolutely no sense
whatsoever
zero
none there's no precedent for it
anywhere in the scriptures
it has absolutely no foundation in
Scripture
so when you hear Christians around the
world talking about this seven years in
which a temple is going to be rebuilt it
is all made up stuff because it's not in
the text
it's not in the text this 70th week
has already been fulfilled but many
Christians don't want to see it and
there's a reason why
there is a reason why come back with me
to the screen
you see in this Gap Theory there is
there is a gap between the 69th and the
70th week look at the screen yep the
70th week will be fulfilled at the End
of Time the Antichrist is the one who
makes a covenant with Israel for seven
years in the middle of the seven years
he will break the Covenant and the seven
year period is known as the Great
Tribulation or maybe the latter half of
that seven years of the remaining three
and a half years but I need y'all to see
this
because beloved Jesus is the one that
made the Covenant y'all not Satan not
Satan
not Satan
not seen
the Bible says in Matthew 26 27 and he
that is Jesus Took the cup and gave
thanks and gave it to them saying
drinking all of it for this is the blood
of my new testament which is shed for
many for the remissions of sins watch
this watch this let's go back let's go
back he shall confirm the Covenant with
many for one week let's go forward let's
go forward drinky all of it for this is
my blood in the New Testament which is
said for
what's the word
four
many he's literally using the same words
so watch this if the Covenant if the
messenger of the Covenant Malachi 3 1
began preaching this message in 27 A.D
when he was baptized and he begins
bringing the message of the Covenant
confirming the Covenant beloved then
three and a half years later is when
Jesus is about to be crucified in other
words in the middle of the week
come on y'all
in the middle of the 70th week
Jesus is breaking bread and giving this
wine saying this is the blood of my
Covenant which is shed for many
you remember what happens when Jesus
died right
when Jesus died listen to what the text
says listen to what the text says
remember this in the midst of the week
he shall cause the sacrifice and
oblation to cease so here's what happens
here's what's happening
for Christians to buy into this 70 week
the 70th week Theory this seven years of
tribulation
because the temple was destroyed in 70
A.D in order to make this seven years
come true there has to be a rebuilt
Temple hence you hear all these
Christians misapplying prophecy talking
about a temple to be rebuilt in
Jerusalem when the Bible says no such
thing
the temple was destroyed in 70 A.D
in order for the seven year tribulation
to work there has to be a rebuilt Temple
so that at the end of this three and a
half years they can stop these
sacrifices and offerings that were
started up again when the temple is
rebuilt that is not what the text is
saying beloved Jesus is the one that put
an end to sacrifices and offerings when
he died in the midst of the week when
the veil of the temple Earl was red was
rent into signify that an Earthly Temple
is of no more significance to God
why because now we are to look to a
Heavenly Sanctuary where Jesus now
dwells as our high priest this is why
the Bible says in Hebrews chapter 10
verse 5 and 6 wherefore when he cometh
into the world he saves sacrifices and
offering thou was not but a body that
has prepared me in burnt offerings and
sacrifices for sin thou has had no
pleasure then said I lo I come and the
volume of the book is written it is
written of me to do thy will o God above
when he said sacrifice and offering and
burnt offerings and offering for sin
thou it's not neither has pleasure
therein which are offered by the law
then he said lo I come to do thy will oh
God he taketh away the first that he may
establish the second are y'all following
it is Jesus not Satan that made a
covenant with many it is Jesus that
brought the sacrifices and offerings to
an end it is not Satan sometime in the
future it happened in the past
notice the next text verse 27 and for
the overspreading of Abominations he
shall make it desolate well how was the
sanctuary and the temple and the city
left desolate Jesus just before his
crucifixion says these words o Jerusalem
Jerusalem thou that kill us the prophets
and stone with them which are sent unto
thee how often would I have gathered thy
children together even as a hand Gap
with her chicks under her wings and you
would not behold your house
is left unto you what
desolate
now watch this guys this is happening
in the middle of the 70th week what does
that mean
what does that mean
is probation closes is Israel cut off
they're not
because there is yet three and a half
years left in the prophecy it's 70 weeks
not 69 not 69 and a half it's 70 weeks
and so despite their rejection of them
it should have been done right there
are y'all catching me it should have
been done for Israel right there
but no no no no no
that's not what happens
you see
Jesus pours out
the Holy Spirit
on the disciples
and where does he send them
what what are this what is this
disciples mean what is their first
mission where does he send them does he
send them to the Gentiles
nope
he sends them to his people
because God is so long suffering he
sends them to his people and he's like
okay you got you all got three and a
half more years there's a parable of a
tree of a tree that that Jesus gets
where he says man this tree is no good
and and and and it's been up for this
long and then they're told to leave it
another year it's a total of three and a
half years before this tree is cut down
I need you to understand
when when Israel rejected the Messiah
rejected his sacrifice on their behalf
God still said all right we're going to
give him a chance so he pours out the
spirit on the disciples and they go to
the lost sheep of the House of Israel
William that's where they go
that's where they go
and Peter now begins to preach and
notice when Peter preaches Acts 2 verse
37 now when they heard this they were
pricked in their hearts and said unto
Peter and to the rest of the Apostles
men and Brethren what shall we do
there are people that are repenting
then Peter said unto them repent and be
baptized every one of you in the name of
Jesus Christ for the remission of sins
and and you shall receive the gift of
the Holy Ghost this is what's happening
people are accepting Christ they're
receiving the Messiah Acts 2 39 for the
promises unto you and to your children
and to all that are far off even as many
as our Lord God shall call again
again in Acts chapter 5 we see then
Peter and the apostles answered and said
let me go back let me go back then Peter
and the apostles answered and said we
ought to obey God rather than men the
god of our fathers raised up Jesus whom
he slew and hanged on a tree him has got
exalted with his right hand to be a
prince and a savior to give repentance
to Israel and forgiveness of sins so for
three and a half years the disciples are
striving and working to have to to to
turn Israel as a nation to accept the
Messiah and I want you to take a guess
with me what happens at the end of that
three and a half years what happens at
the end of that what happens at the end
of the 70th week
let's go to the book of Acts chapter 7.
this is what happens in 34 A.D
Stephen is stoned
Stephen becomes the first Christian
martyr
he is stoned by the body of Israel
by the by the high court of Israel if
you will as a nation not individuals as
a nation they're saying we reject what
you have to offer
and and they bring Stephen to Stone him
and I want you to note Stephen gives
this speech in in in in Acts chapter 7
which is very different from Daniel's
prayer in Daniel chapter nine you see in
Daniel chapter nine Daniel was praying
for you know for forgiveness for mercy
and then the the prophecy comes 70 weeks
70 times seven now watch this y'all
I need y'all to see this
when Stephen speaks when Peter was
preaching right when he's on a day of
Pentecost in the middle of the 70th week
he's preaching and he's saying to them
what repent right there's a call for
repentance when Stephen gets up to speak
just before he's killed
there is no call for repentance
it's simply judgment
did y'all hear what I just said
Stephen is condemning the nation he
doesn't say repent he doesn't say he he
begins to rehearse how good God has been
to the nation and then he says these
words at chapter 7 verse 51 you
stiff-necked you stiff-necked and
uncircumcised in heart and ears you do
always resist the Holy Ghost as your
fathers did so do you which of the
prophets have you not have your fathers
not persecuted and they have slain them
with shoe before the coming of the just
one of whom you have been now the
betrayers and murderers whom you have
received whom whom have who have
received the law about the disposition
of the Angels
and have not kept it
and how do they respond when they heard
these things they were cut to the heart
and they Nast on him
they Nast on him with their teeth but he
being full of the Holy Ghost looked up
steadfastly into heaven and saw the
glory of God and Jesus standing on the
right hand of God watch this and when
they heard these things I'm sorry
next slide next slide here we go and
they cried out with a loud voice and
stopped their ears and ran upon him with
one Accord and cast them out of the city
and stoned him
do y'all see this
they stoned him
they stole him
they see Stephen says I see Jesus
standing at the right hand of God as if
he was seeing your probation has closed
your judgment
is settled I extend it to you not human
Mercy seven times I extend it to you 70
times seven
times seven watch let's go to the screen
457 BC Daniel is praying for mercy and
forgiveness of sins 27 A.D John the
Baptist his message Mercy repent 21 27
A.D to 31 a day Jesus's message
forgiveness of sins 31 A.D Peter
preaches repent The Outpost of the Holy
Spirit Peter preaches repent 34 A.D
Stephen condemnation
no call for repentance no nothing just
condemnation
listen
the 70-week prophecy you guys
the 70-week prophecy was completely
fulfilled by 34 A.D
there was no Gap there was no seven
years in the future with a temple being
rebuilt in fact in Daniel 9 27 the last
verse of this prophecy it says that the
temple would lay desolate even until the
consummation and that determined shall
be poured out upon the desolate this
happened beloved even though even though
34 A.D was the closing of the 70 weeks
the consummation
that would be poured out upon a desolate
came in 70 A.D this is why Jesus says in
Matthew 24 21 Jesus went out and
departed from the temple and his
disciples came to him for the show in
the building of the temple and Jesus
said unto him seeing out all these
things verily out saying to you there
shall not be left here one stone upon
another that shall not be thrown down
Jesus was foreshadowing was foretelling
of the future destruction of Jerusalem
in 70 A.D
this is why Jesus said in Matthew 12 39
he answered and said unto them an evil
and adulterous generation seeketh a sign
and there shall be no son given it but
the sign of Jonah the prophets
do y'all understand this
the sign of Jonah the prophet the sign
of Jonah the prophet
is the fact that remember Jonah was in
the belly of the Earth for three days
and
three nights
and and at the end of the years in fact
Matthew 12 verse 40. let's look at it
first Jonah was three days and three
nights in the whale's belly so shall the
son of man be three days and three
nights in the heart of the Earth
the men of Nineveh shall rise in
judgment with this generation and shall
condemn it because they repented at the
preaching of Jonas and behold a greater
than Jonah is here now I need you on a
catch this because remember Jonah was in
the belly of the Earth for three days
and three nights pointing to the death
burial and resurrection of Christ
however
Jonah went to preach at Nineveh and and
and probation
Jonah literally said yet 40 days
and the City of Nineveh will be
overthrown
the city of Nineveh repented 40 days
came and the city stood it was not
overthrown
Israel watch this y'all
Jerusalem
had rejected Christ
Jonas three days and three nights and
you know what Jesus Does
Justice Jonah
gave 40 days before the destruction of
the city
if you take 31 A.D the year that Christ
is crucified
and count 40 years it brings you to 70
A.D
because they rejected the sign of Jonah
the three his death burial and
Resurrection 40 years later
the city is destroyed
now I need a lot of watches we're almost
done we're almost finished
in Acts chapter 7 verse 58 the Bible
says this
when Stephen is stoned there was a
witness there by the name of Saul
I'm going somewhere this and I need your
followers all right we are getting ready
to wrap this up there was a witness
there by the name of Saul the Bible says
in Acts 8 1 and Saul was consenting unto
his death that is Stephen's death and at
that time there was a great persecution
against the church which was at
Jerusalem and they were all scattered
abroad throughout the region of Judea
and Samaria except the apostles now
it's in Acts chapter 9 that we read
about Saul's conversion
so as Stephen is being is killed Saul is
right there who is going to become the
man named Paul who has been called to be
the missionary
to who
foreign
Acts chapter 9 verse 15 but the Lord
said unto him go thy way for he is a
chosen vessel unto me to Bear my name
before the Gentiles and Kings and the
children of Israel so so now watch this
here's what we need to understand
you see it's in Acts chapter 10 that
Peter receives his vision about the
unclean beast and how what God has
cleansed thou shall not call common or
unclean and the vision in the vision
Peter comes to realize that God has
opened salvation to the Gentiles
are y'all following he's open salvation
to the Gentiles in Acts chapter 10 verse
34 it says this then Peter opened his
mouth and said of a truth I perceive
that God is no respecter of persons but
in every nation he that fearth him and
worketh righteousness is accepted of him
so when Cornelius is receives the
outpouring of the Holy Spirit it is the
first time that Jews come to realize
wait a minute
you mean God can use a gentile
God could use a gentile for what watch
this y'all
why was Israel called
in First Peter chapter 2 verse 9 the
Bible says but you are a chosen
generation a royal priesthood a holy
nation A peculiar people that you should
sow forth the Praises of him who called
you out of Darkness into his marvelous
life come back with me come back to the
screen with me please
the mission of Israel was to show forth
the Praises of God
to the world
that was their mission Israel I'm
calling you to show forth my praises to
the whole world
but you know what Israel rejected that
mission
not wait wait Jesus is part of that
we don't believe the Messiah we don't
believe in the one who is able to
forgive sins to to finish transgression
to make an end of sin to bring an
everlasting righteousness we don't
believe in that one who is able to put
an end to change no no no no no no no no
and so if you reject the very one
whom God said to forgive sins to put an
end to sins to to cause a sacrifice and
oblations to cease then you don't have
an understanding of the Gospel
how can I use you for a mission that you
don't understand
how
all right so since you all have rejected
the main ingredient in this Mission
which is the Messiah that I'm going to
raise up on new people for that mission
it doesn't mean that Israel cannot be
saved that Jews still cannot be saved it
simply meant I gotta raise somebody else
up for the mission you can still be
saved
thank you
this is not an anti-israel message it's
you can still be saved however
I'm not depending on you
to bring the if you're going to be saved
by the way you're going to have to come
back to this 70 weeks and understand who
this Messiah is
so now God is raising up a People First
Peter chapter 2 10 which in time past
were not a people but are now the people
of God which had not obtained Mercy but
have now obtained Mercy do you see this
all right
so guys
we have just completed the 70-week
prophecy I don't know how long that took
me but
if I was going to break it down that
even a child could understand it then I
needed to do it this way okay
but now I need to explain to you
something
you see
this is prophecy and the Bible tells us
the Bible tells the fact let's go to the
screen right here and I just want you to
see it clearly all right so here we see
457 BC if you count 69 weeks or 483 year
it takes you to 27 A.D you count the
middle of that week and by the way some
people say well did Jesus die in 31 A.D
or was it 32 A.D or was it 33 A.D listen
now it doesn't matter let me tell you
why
because the prophecy says that he would
die in the midst of the week it doesn't
mean exactly in the middle of the week
so I believe we believe that Jesus died
in 31 A.D but if it was 30 A.D it does
nothing to the prophecy because it's
saying that he would die sometime in the
middle of this week that's all plain and
simple
so you got 2780 for the beginning of the
week and 34 A.D for the ending of the
week
and in fact if you if you know that the
if you look at the Jerusalem Council
which I believe was about 52 or 53 A.D
and you count Paul's missionary journey
14 years back before he was he says I
spent three years alone by myself and
then count three years back it literally
brings you to 34 A.D as the year of his
uh of his um conversion
okay so now you've seen that at bird's
eye view the Bible says in second Peter
1 19 we have also a more sure word of
Prophecy where unto you do well that you
take heed as into a light that shines in
a dark place until the day Dawn and the
day star arise in your heart prophecy is
like a torch y'all prophecy is like a
torch but watch this in Leviticus 10 1
the Bible says the sons of Aaron took
either of them his Center and put fire
therein and put incense thereon and
offered Strange Fire before the Lord let
me break this down for you
false prophecy beloved is Strange Fire
we're wrapping this up false prophecy
beloved is Strange Fire and what this
false prophecy or Strange Fire of this
so-called seven years of tribulation
does it does several things number one
here's what it does
it lends Credence to the teaching of
once saved always saved
what Pastor listen
if Israel is still the chosen people of
God you know what that means
you can reject the Messiah and still be
the chosen people of God
isn't that something else
you can actually reject Christ the Bible
says the Bible says in first John
chapter 5 verse 11 and 12.
and this is the record
that God has given us
eternal life
that God has given us eternal life and
this life is in his son he that has the
son has life he that does not have the
son does not have life so what is then
if if Christians are of the
understanding that that Israel is God's
Remnant no matter what
then what that says about the character
of God is this
you can reject Christ
and still be God's people and man if you
can reject Christ and still be God's
people
then maybe God really doesn't care too
much about how obedient I am because if
Israel was disobedient and even rejected
the Messiah at least I say I believe in
Jesus so that ought to account for
something right
and and so and subconsciously there's a
downplaying of obedience and even
keeping the law just as Israel did
because look if they're still the chosen
people of God
then I'm good to go
and so and so it is no wonder that there
is this heavy heavy
israel-centric approach in Christianity
at large you know bless Israel in fact
you know remember what Jesus said in
what the Bible says in Genesis 12 I will
bless them that bless thee and curse him
that cursed thee and indeed shall all
the families of the earth be blessed so
now to the Christian world's like look
if I don't need to or I don't even
really need to obey God I can I can
curse people out and get angry at people
who are of a different political
persuasion than Christians ought to be
because we know all Christians ought to
be of this political persuasion and so I
can be angry I can cuss people out I can
tell people they're going to hell I can
do all kinds of things as long as I pray
for Israel
that I'm showing
how much
I love God
pray for Israel pray for Israel pray for
Israel
cursing people out
winking your eye at corruption
all in the name
of Jesus
pray for Israel
now should we be praying for Israel
absolutely
so we'd be praying for Jamaica
so we be praying for America
so we'd be praying for Russia
Beloved the Bible tells us in Revelation
chapter 14 that there is a message to go
forth to Every Nation Kindred tongue and
people God has no special Nation
physical Nation on this Earth his nation
is his people anybody that accepts
Christ
whether you are a literal Jew or a
gentile God's nation is made up of
everybody that accepts Christ yes Deanda
all lives matter
yes yes yes yes yes yes God doesn't love
some lives more than other lives God
doesn't love some Nations more than
other nations All Nations matter Israel
was simply chosen to be the vehicle for
the mission but because they rejected
the centerpiece of the mission
God said okay I got to use somebody else
I gotta use somebody else it doesn't
mean that that Israel is is not lost and
Jews no it just means you're not taking
on this Mission I gotta raise somebody
else and I need you to understand that
anyone that is going to be saved must
come through the same door must come
through the same individual and that
individual is Jesus Christ you see
finally This Strange Fire produces a
Christianity that has no understanding
of the work of the Antichrist
no understanding of the work of the
Antichrist because now you're on this
track of well in order for prophecy to
be fulfilled there's going to be a
temple rebuilt and we've got to support
Jerusalem because if we don't support
Jerusalem then the things that are
supposed to happen to bring about the
end times where this Temple is rebuilt
and The Seven Year treaty is made with
Israel and then broken three and a half
years in three and a half years after it
and then at the end of the three and a
half years Jesus comes many people don't
even realize if if that were true we
would know the very year that Jesus
comes
because of hmm all right so if the if
the Temple's been rebuilt and the seven
years starts today and then we count
three and a half years and we can expect
the Antichrist is going to put an end to
the sacrifices then we know that three
and a half years later Jesus comes
y'all see this
so listen
my appeal
is is going to be a very childlike
appeal right now I got two verses
Hosea 4 6
Hosea 4 6 and then second Timothy 2 15.
Hosea 4 6 says this my people are
destroyed falak of knowledge I just want
to stop there my people are destroyed
for lack of knowledge beloved
there are so many Christians
there are so many Christians who
just don't study the word of God for
themselves
they they go along with what is popular
they go along with what is expected to
be okay so our culture and our culture
Christianity represents X Y and Z so
we're gonna do that thing
and we're not studying the Bible
we're depending upon other people to
break down the Bible for us listen
the appeal is simple and it's appeal of
God it's an appeal from God
study to show thyself approved second
Timothy 2 15.
study
to show thyself approved approved unto
God a Workman that needeth not be
ashamed rightly dividing the word of
Truth see those little kids
Jesus said I said you would come like a
little child you shot a no-wise enter
the kingdom of heaven
the appeal today is simple beloved
these things that we often tell
ourselves are too complicated for us to
understand too complicated for us to
explain to the congregation too
complicated for me because I don't
really know the Bible to listen y'all
with prayer and asking the Holy Spirit
to to guide you into the truth
you can know the truth and the truth
will set you free
will set you free now I know for many of
you watching you've you may have heard
this before you've heard this before
you've heard this seven weeks before and
maybe you haven't heard it broken down
in this much detail and maybe you have
but listen your
there are millions of Christians out
there in the world today there is there
are government policies being made based
upon a false understanding of the
70-week prophecy
government policies in America
based upon Christian docking and an
incorrect understanding of Prophecy
which leads to the uh to the picture
that God
favors some Nations over others God
favors some people over up over others
that's not who our God is
but if you think God is like that then
you're going to start acting the same
way
because by beholding you become changed
if you don't have the right picture of
God
there's a reason Jesus said if it were
possible even the very elect would be
deceived and I'm telling you this
teaching right here this teaching right
here
it is deceiving Millions
some of y'all are saying millions of
people need to see this message you're
right
you're right
millions of people maybe not for me from
whoever it needs to preach it millions
of people need to understand this why
not you why don't you take this message
and share it with your with your friends
share with your family share with you
why don't you take this message and
learn it for yourself because they might
be like you know I don't like
bald-headed people who preach okay but
they're like you you take this message
learn how to deliver it break it down
and share it with your family share it
with your friends because you know what
they love you and they trust you sharing
break it down
let us study this show ourselves
approved beloved and if there's any of
you who have who who are sinners for the
first time and you've doubted Jesus I
hope that this prophecy has shown you
that Jesus is exactly who he says he is
this prophecy could not be manipulated
you understand
this prophecy is the it it sets the seal
that Jesus is who he says he is and if
you don't understand this prophecy
beloved you're not going to understand
all the other prophecies that follow it
so number one appeal study the show
thyself approve number two appeal if
you're watching this for the first time
and you see this as truth and you
understand Pastor I need to I I haven't
even heard of y'all before but I want to
know more about this I want to
understand the Bible like this I'm going
to invite you to get in touch with our
Bible worker and we'll set up Bible
studies with you if you want to receive
Christ for the first time I'm going to
ask get in touch with put a one in the
chat in fact let's let's put Rick's um
contact information in the chat there it
is and if you want Bible study because
you're hearing this for the first time
if you want
I see you Richie if you want to
understand the truth as it is in in
Christ the truth of the word of God
please we will be more than willing to
study with you we will be more than
willing to lead you into studies either
so that you can be baptized or if you've
been baptized already that you can be
affirmed in the truth beloved our goal
is to get as many people into the
Kingdom of Heaven as possible because
that's Jesus's goal
let's pray Heavenly Father
thank you for speaking to us today
thank you for breaking the word of God
down so that we could understand it
thank you for taking complex
complex thoughts
complex themes
and making it so that we can put our
minds around it and grasp it Lord may we
not make the same mistake that Israel
made in the days of Jesus that it
doesn't Messiah doesn't matter that we
can still cling on to God
without obeying him
please Lord
forgive us put an end
to transgression for us may we accept
the son
that the 70-week prophecy may become a
reality in our lives
we thank you Jesus for hearing and
answering this prayer because we ask it
in the precious and holy name of Jesus
Amen
and a man
we'll put up this last slide for those
of you who maybe want to take a shot of
the QR code
um
to enroll in Bible studies if you have
not heard these things before we are
we would love to be able to study with
you all right so there's a QR code may
God bless you we want to invite you to
join us on alter live which is where we
have our Afterglow discussion we talk
about the Sabbath school we talk about
the Divine service we talk about the
sermon and we just share and uh
encourage one another so
um we're going to put the link up in the
chat if it has not already been put in
the chat and may God bless you as um
as you uh
uh continue to follow him and search the
scriptures amen
thank you for joining us today if this
is your first time worshiping with us
please check out our website at
livingmanna.church we are not just here
for Sabbath service we have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health physical health weekly prayer
service financial help and proving the
existence of God it is our desire that
our programming will continue to bless
you please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the Gospel of Jesus Christ
[Music]
thank you